Fame makes monkeys of us all.
Better Man is a music, drama film directed by Michael Gracey.
Follow Robbie Williams' journey from childhood, to being the youngest member of chart-topping boyband Take That, through to his unparalleled
achievements as a record-breaking solo artist – all the while confronting the challenges that stratospheric fame and success can bring.
Robbie Williams (voice), played by Robbie Williams.
Robbie Williams, played by Jonno Davies.
Peter, played by Steve Pemberton.
Betty, played by Alison Steadman.
Janet, played by Kate Mulvany.
Nate, played by Frazer Hadfield.
Better Man is a 2024 biographical jukebox musical drama film directed by Michael
Gracey from a screenplay by Gracey, Simon Gleeson and Oliver Cole.
It is based on the life of the English singer Robbie Williams and stars Williams, Jonno Davies, Steve Pemberton and Alison
Steadman, and is a co-production between Australia, China, France, the United Kingdom and the United States.
Development on Better Man began in February 2021, after Gracey was
announced as director and co-writer alongside Gleeson and Cole.
Williams is portrayed as an anthropomorphic chimpanzee, performed by Davies using motion capture, and co-voiced by Williams: this was
due to Williams' perception of himself as a "performing monkey" and Gracey's vision of the film as a "satirical musical".
No character comments on his appearance.
Williams also re-recorded several songs from his discography for the film.
Principal photography began in May 2022 and lasted until June 2023, with filming locations including
Docklands Studios in Melbourne, Regent Street and the Royal Albert Hall in London and Krnjača.
Better Man premiered at the 51st Telluride Film Festival on 30 August 2024 and was theatrically released in the United States on 25 December, by
Paramount Pictures, and in the United Kingdom and Australia a day later, respectively by Entertainment Film Distributors and Roadshow Films.
It grossed $22.5 million worldwide, becoming a
box-office bomb, but received positive reviews.
Better Man won nine AACTA Awards, including for Best Film, and was nominated for Best Visual Effects at the
Academy Awards, Critics' Choice Awards, BAFTA Film Awards and Visual Effects Society Awards.
The film explores themes of depression, drug addiction,
musical, biography, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.